Guide to the Michael Lally Papers MSS.361
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II. Screenwriting, Plays, and Acting, 1960s, 1972-2011, undated; 13 Linear Feet in 20 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, 2 cartons, 1 flat box, 1 oversize flat box, and 2 flat-file folders; 3 Gigabytes in 24 computer files; 11 sound cassettes (dat); 11 audiocassettes; 42 videocassette
  - Subseries II.B. Acting and Voice Over Work, 1978-2008; 6 Linear Feet in 4 manuscript boxes, one half manuscript box, 1 flat box, 1 oversize flat box, 1 record carton, and 1 flat-file folder; 11 sound cassettes (dat); 11 audiocassettes; 42 videocassettes (vhs); 1 videocassettes (betacam); 9 videocassettes (u-matic); 1 videocassettes (video 8); 2 Gigabytes in 23 computer files
    This subseries includes material related to Lally's work as a film, stage, and voice over actor in Los Angeles during the 1980s through the 2000s. Notated movie and television episode actor scripts include Basic Instinct, Cool World, Deadwood, Ed, JAG, Father Dowling Mysteries, Ramona Has Two Lovers, and White Fang. Sound and video recordings in both digital and analog form contain demo reels used for auditions with samples of Lally's appearances in television show episodes and movies, as well as his voice work in advertising commercials. This subseries also contains publicity for movies and television shows, including posters and advertising booklets for Phobia, The Nesting, and Last Rites. This subseries also contains Lally's play programs, call sheets, and acting contracts.
    - Acting Audition Demo Clips, undated; cuid36276 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_361_ER_12)
    - Acting Contracts, 1993-2003 (Box 100, Folder 1-5)
      Conditions Governing Access
      These files are restricted until Michael Lally's death. Personal information must be redacted before they are available for use by researchers.
    - Call Sheets and Contact Lists, 1979-2004 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Commercial Work -- Campaign for Freedom, 2002; cuid36266 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_361_ER_2)
    - Deadwood Images, 2004; cuid36267 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_361_ER_3)
    - Film Soundtrack -- Eleni Karaindrou Ulysses' Gaze, 1995; cuid36273 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_361_ER_9)
    - Movie Publicity Material and Posters, 1980-1981 (Box 79, Folder 5, Flat-file-folder 18)
    - Play Programs, 1981, 1989, undated (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Publicity, 1979-2000 (Box 51, Folder 3-6, Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Scripts -- Balm in Gilead, circa 1983 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Scripts -- Basic Instinct, 1991 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Scripts -- Boomerang, undated (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Scripts -- Cool World, 1991 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Scripts -- Deadwood, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Scripts -- Diagnosis Murder, 1994 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Scripts -- Ed, 2001 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Scripts -- Greenpoint Tavern, undated (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Scripts -- Human Condition, undated (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Scripts -- JAG, 1997-1998 (Box 52, Folder 9-10)
    - Scripts -- Father Dowling Mysteries, 1990 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Scripts -- Last Grave, undated (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Scripts -- Last Rites, 1978 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Scripts -- Law & Order, 2000 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Scripts -- NYPD Blue, 1995-1996 (Box 53, Folder 3-6)
    - Scripts -- Phobia, 1979 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Scripts -- Ramona Has Two Lovers, 1989 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Scripts -- The Rapture, 1990 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Scripts -- The Technical Writer, 2002 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Scripts -- White Fang, 1990 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Scripts -- Untitled Movie, undated (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Sound Recordings -- Voice Over Audition Demos, 1983-2001 (Box 82)
      11 DATs; 11 Audiocassettes
    - Video Recordings -- Movies, Plays, TV Show Episodes, and Demos used for Auditions, 1980s-2000s (Box 81, Box 82)
      42 VHS; 1 Beta; 9 U-matic; 1-- 8mm videocassette
    - Voice Over Sample, undated; cuid36272 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_361_ER_8)
    - Voice Over Work, 2005, 2008, undated (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Subseries II.C. Correspondence, 1972-2011; 1.5 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes and 1 flat-file folder
    This subseries contains correspondence from friends and colleagues Lally accumulated while living in Los Angeles as an actor, playwright, and screenwriter in the 1980s through the 2000s. Of note are letters from actors Sharon Stone, Carrie Fisher, and Michael O'Keefe. Letters and a 1987 collage Lally by artist Paul Harryn can also be found in this subseries. Poetry written by friends for Lally's 50th birthday is in this subseries. This subseries also contains correspondence for Lally's Poetry in Motion project, which was a spoken word series co-created with Eve Brandstein in 1988. Lally's series brought together poets and Hollywood celebrities including Alec Baldwin, Robert Downey, Jr., Ally Sheedy, and Michael O'Keefe for readings. See Series I.C. for publicity files on this project.
    - Acting Correspondence, 1984-2011 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Anderson, Jo, 1991 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Bakshi, Ralph, undated (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Baldwin, Alec, 1992-2008 (Box 54, Folder 6-7)
    - Baribeault, Joan, 1985 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Binder, Mike, 1987 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Christopher, Dennis, 1984-2011 (Box 54, Folder 10-11)
    - Fisher, Carrie, 1986-1992 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Harryn, Paul, 1987-1988, 1994 (Box 54, Folder 13, Flat-file-folder 1 Left)
    - Hunter, Neith, 1992 (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - Los Angeles and California, 1980-2006 (Box 54, Folder 15-19, Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Lourd, Blaine, 2004-2010 (Box 55, Folder 2-4)
    - McCollister, Kevin, 2003, undated (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - O'Keefe, Michael, 1983-2010 (Box 55, Folder 6-7)
    - Perez, Ruth and Ruben, 2000-2005 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Poetry -- Michael Lally on 50th Birthday, 1992 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Poetry in Motion and Hollywood Review, 1987, 1999, undated (Box 55, Folder 10-13)
    - Roddan, Brooks, 2000-2005 (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - Rose, Jamie, 1989-2011 (Box 55, Folder 15)
    - Stein, Nathan, 1992-2004 (Box 55, Folder 16)
    - Stone, Sharon, 1997-2000 (Box 55, Folder 17, Box 56, Folder 1-3)
    - Westphall, Robin, 1972-1976 (Box 56, Folder 4)
- Series III. Personal, 1930-2012; 12 Linear Feet in 20 manuscript boxes, 2 flat boxes, 2 custom flat boxes, and 2 flat-file folders; 2 audiocassettes; 1 websites in 1 archived website.; 153.9 Megabytes in 44 computer files
  This series is divided into two subseries:
  Subseries III.A. General
  Subseries III.B. Correspondence
  Material is arranged within each subseries in alphabetical order by file title.
  This series contains material related to Lally's personal life including school papers and ephemera; scrapbooks; journals and notebooks; press interviews and clippings; address books; calendars and date books; and correspondence with family and friends. This series also includes electronic files containing casual and professional images of Lally. An archived version of his blog, http://lallysalley.blogspot.com/ can also be found in this series. The blog was first captured in June 2019.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued annually.
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  - Subseries III.A. General, 1930-2011; 12 Linear Feet in 16 manuscript boxes, 2 flat boxes, 3 oversize flat boxes, 2 flat-file folders; 2 audiocassettes; 1 websites in 1 archived website.; 153.9 Megabytes in 44 computer files
    This subseries contains Lally's address books, calendars, and daybooks from 1982 to 2011 which track his daily routine and appointments. Wall calendar pages with illustrations by George Schneeman, and a 1979 Koff calendar with nude photographs of male poets Lally, Charles Bukowski, Bill Berkson, Tom Carey, John Godfrey, and Bill Kushner can also be found in this subseries. Material from Lally's time attending St. Benedict's Preparatory School, Trinity College, and the University of Iowa includes class papers, publications, MFA thesis notes, workshop files, and yearbooks. This subseries also contains documentation of Lally's service in the Air Force in the 1960s, as well as files related to Lally and his first wife Lee's marriage and divorce, dating from the 1960s to the 1990s. Journals and notebooks from 1962 to the 1990s contain vacation diaries, an acting journal, and financial records kept by Lally. Scrapbooks contain juvenilia from Lally's birth and early childhood, clippings, play programs, publicity, and documentation of his political activism in the 1960s. This subseries also includes political posters by Sharon Gregory and political buttons collected by Lally. Clippings and transcripts of interviews profiling Lally date from 1979 to 2011. This subseries also contains files on his grants and awards, resumes, and an original piece of artwork by Lally of friends Ray and Betsi DiPalma from the 1970s.
    - Address Books, undated (Box 56, Folder 5-7, Box 57, Folder 1-3)
    - Advertisements and Event Posters, undated (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Air Force Records, 1962-1968 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Allen Ginsberg's American Celebration, 1997 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Appointment Books and Calendars, 1982-2011 (Box 57, Folder 6, Box 58, Folder 1-5, Box 59, Folder 1-4, Box 60, Box 61, Box 62, Box 63, Box 64)
    - Artwork, circa 1970s (Flat-file-folder 1 Left)
    - Awards, Grants, and Commendations, 1970-2006 (Box 65, Folder 1-2)
    - A Bestiary for Caitlin, 1968 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Boy Scout Cards, 1953-1955 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Broadsides, undated (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Business and Membership Cards, Ephemera, 1967-1988 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Buttons, 1992, undated (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Casual and Professional Portraits, 2004-2007; cuid36268 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_361_ER_4)
    - Clippings, 1974-2007 (Box 65, Folder 7-10, Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Daddy [James A. Lally] Memorabilia, 1930-1949 (Box 65, Folder 11)
    - Interviews with Lally, 1977-2010 (Box 66, Folder 1-6)
    - Journals and Notebooks, 1962-1990, undated (Box 66, Folder 7-10, Box 67, Folder 1-9, Box 68, Folder 1-4, Box 75, Folder 9-10)
    - Lally's Alley Archived Website, 2019-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
      Appraisal
      Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored.
      Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of lallysalley.blogspot.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
      Personal culture blog of Michael Lally.
    - Lee and Michael Wedding and Divorce, 1964, 1977-1978 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Resume, 1974-1995, undated (Box 68, Folder 6-9)
    - Scrapbook, 1942-1974 (Box 76)
    - Scrapbook, 1975-1982 (Box 78, Flat-file-folder 1 Left, Flat-file-folder 18)
    - Scrapbook, 1982-1995 (Box 77)
    - Songs, 1960-2012 (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Sound Recordings -- Rain Worthington, 1976, 1985 (Box 83)
      2 audiocassettes
    - St. Benedict's Preparatory School, 1956-1961, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 1-5, Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Trinity College, 1971, 1973 (Box 69, Folder 6-7)
    - University of Iowa, 1967-1969 (Box 69, Folder 8-11, Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Wall Calendars, 1979, 2000-2001 (Flat-file-folder 1 Left)
  - Subseries III.B. Correspondence, 1949-2012; 2.5 Linear Feet in 5 manuscript boxes
    This subseries contains correspondence from 1966 to 1997 with Lally's friends and family. Correspondence from Lally's first wife Lee while he served in the Air Force describe their courtship and wedding plans, as well as cards and notes after their marriage. Letters from friends to Lee Lally from the 1960s and 1970s kept by Michael Lally are in this series. This subseries also contains letters from Lally's other two wives and his three children. Letters from Lally's parents James and Irene date from 1949 to 1973, sharing news of the family and events in their lives. Correspondence from Lally's siblings are also in this subseries, including letters from 1953-2010 from brother Campion Lally who served as a priest at Franciscan Chapel Center in Japan. A significant portion of the letters from friends in this subseries were sent while Lally was serving in the Air Force in the 1960s.
    - Angela, 1962-1963 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Askew, Lynn and Teddy, 1964 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Bambi, 1963-1989 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Buchs, Doug, 1963-1964 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Cousin Kathy, 1979, 1985-1992 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Dasko, Maureen, 1962 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Dolores, 1963 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Dunaways, 1966-1977 (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Fensom, Harry, 1962 (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Freeman, Kathy -- Berlin, 1970-1973 (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Graham, Kenny, 1964-1968 (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - Harris, Gene, 1963-1966 (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - Harvey, Dick, 1963-1969 (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - Harvey, Roy and Karen, 1965-1986 (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - Hewlett (Resta), Susan, 1963-1970 (Box 70, Folder 16)
    - Johnson, Al and Sissy, 1964-1965, 1982 (Box 70, Folder 17)
    - Jones, Della, 1963 (Box 70, Folder 18)
    - Lally, Caitlin, 1986-2012 (Box 71, Folder 1-2)
    - Lally, Campion, 1953-2010 (Box 71, Folder 3-5)
    - Lally, Flynn and Jaina, 1998-2002 (Box 71, Folder 6-7)
    - Lally, Irene and James, 1949-1973 (Box 72, Folder 1-3)
    - Lally Koch, Irene, 1964-2010 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Lally, Jim (Buddy), 1962-1993 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Lally, Joan, 1962-1984 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Lally, Lee, 1962-1977 (Box 72, Folder 7-9, Box 73, Folder 1-4)
    - Lally, Miles, undated (Box 73, Folder 5-6)
    - Larabee, Linda, 1961-1970 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Friends, 1962-1965, 1983 (Box 73, Folder 8, Flat-file-folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Irish, 1975-1995 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - New Jersey Friends, 1966 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Other Family, 1985-1998 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Ryker, Val, undated (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Tandy, Bill, 1966 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Wicks, Charlie, 1962-1968 (Box 74, Folder 6)